<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>practices on fn:join</title><link>https://fnjoin.com/tags/practices/</link><description>Recent content in practices on fn:join</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><managingEditor>contact@fnjoin.com (Salman Malik, Archie Cowan)</managingEditor><webMaster>contact@fnjoin.com (Salman Malik, Archie Cowan)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fnjoin.com/tags/practices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Accelerate Your Deployment Velocity with Feature flags</title><link>https://fnjoin.com/post/2021-12-04-accelerate-with-feature-flags/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@fnjoin.com (Salman Malik, Archie Cowan)</author><guid>https://fnjoin.com/post/2021-12-04-accelerate-with-feature-flags/</guid><description>Make Small Iterative Changes We wrote in How Many Deployments Amazon Does in a Day that your team is likely capable of deploying a million times in about 10 years with a little more than 55 engineers by making 2-3 changes per week per engineer to production. When you make that many changes per week, those changes likely aren&amp;rsquo;t complete features. Complete features may have hundreds of small iterative changes of that size with contributions from many people.</description></item><item><title>You Can Match How Many Deployments Amazon Does in a Day</title><link>https://fnjoin.com/post/2021-11-28-how-many-deployments-amazon-does-in-a-day/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@fnjoin.com (Salman Malik, Archie Cowan)</author><guid>https://fnjoin.com/post/2021-11-28-how-many-deployments-amazon-does-in-a-day/</guid><description>Wonder how many deployments Amazon does in a day? In November 2014, Dr. Werner Vogels reported that Amazon achieves 50M deployments a year across their dev, test, and production environments. That&amp;rsquo;s 136k deployments per day or about 1.6 per second. His article describes the systems they created to automate deployment across their infrastructure. That is only one aspect of reaching that astronomical position. You also need a lot of engineers to reach that level of productivity.</description></item></channel></rss>